Hey, let's go
I'm happy as can be
Let's go walkin', you and me
Ready, set
Come on, let's go
Over the hill
Across the field
Through the tunnel we'll go
We'll run across the bridge
And down the bumpy gravel road
Right beneath the spider's web
Ready, set
Let's
Go
Hey, let's go
I'm happy as can be
Let's go walkin', you and me
Ready, set
Come on, let's go
The foxes and
The badgers, too
All come out to play
They all want to explore
The deep and wonderful woods
all day
Look at all my many friends
Ready, set
Let's
Go
Look at all my many friends
Ready, set
Let's
Go
Thanks.
Daddy, you want any caramel candy?
Oh, thank you very much, I would.
Anybody tired yet?
Mm-mmm.
We're almost there.
Good.
Mei, hide.
I thought he was a policeman.
Hi!
Hello there!
Sorry to bother you,
but are your parents around anywhere?
They're out there, in the field.
Thanks a lot.
Hello there!
Looks like we're
going to be neighbors!
Pleasure to meet you.
Good luck in the new house!
- Oh!
- Thank you! See you soon!
Thank you very much.
Everybody out.
Hey!
Hang on.
There.
Hey, Mei, come over here a minute.
Wow!
What are those little things
swimming around?
I don't know.
Goldfish maybe or something?
So do you like it?
- It's terrific!
- Uh-huh.
Come on, Mei, run!
Wait up!
- Can we?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh!  Ha ha!
You be careful, okay?
Oh, sure.
What a lot of neat old junk.
Do you think it's haunted?
- Maybe it is.
- Oh, boy!
Come on, I bet I can beat you
around the house!
Hey, wait a minute!
It's completely rotten.
Uh-oh, it's gonna fall down!
Hey!
Wow, Mei, look up!
What?
Up there!  Look!
Wow, what a tree!
It's giant!
- That's got to be the biggest tree in--
- Ah-choo!
Daddy, look at that
big tree on the mountain!
That's a camphor tree.
Camphor.
Camphor tree!
- Camphor!
- Camphor tree!
Uhh! Oh!
Hey, Mei...
Look, an acorn.
But I want an acorn, too.
Oh, hey, wait a second.
There's some more over there.
Ah!  I have my own acorn right here.
Huh?
Mei, how am I supposed to open
the house up if you're in the way?
- Acorns!
- We found them!
And I found a bunch of them right near the back door.
And they came from way up!
It's true, they came out of the ceiling.
Hmm. Some squirrels
must have dropped them.
Ohh! Squirrels!
Or maybe some other animal,
perhaps a rat.
- Rats?
- But I don't want a dumb rat!
Hey, uh, where am I going to put it?
Um, just bring it here.
I'll open it up for you.
Satsuki, go and open the kitchen door.
- Uh huh.
- Hi!
Here you go.
- Mei, come on.
- That man's funny.
Wait!
Hey, wait up!
You can't catch me
Can, too.
- Uhh.
- Ohh.
Aah!
Hmm.
Ready?
Mm-hmm.
- Bathtubs.
- Great.
- Nothing up there.
- No.
Bathtubs are in there.
We saw something move in there.
A squirrel?
We're not sure.
Well, maybe they were cockroaches,
but, anyway, there were millions of them.
Lots o' little black things.
See anything?
Well, I'm pretty sure
they were dust bunnies.
You mean real dust bunnies,
like in my picture book?
Dust bunnies make much
more sense than ghosts.
Why?
Well, ghosts are a lot harder to see.
But when you suddenly move from a lighted room
to a dark one, you can't see for a second.
And that's when the dust bunnies come out.
Got it?
Boy. Yeah.
Come out! Come out!
Come out!
‭Come on out!
Come out, dust bunnies!
Whadda ya say we get to work now?
We have to figure out where the steps are
that lead up to the attic, right?
What?
So you go find the way up, and
we'll open all the windows upstairs.
- Yeah!
- Hey, wait for me.
No stairs.
No.
Nothing here.
Nope. Nothing there.
Nothing there.
Nobody in this room.
Nobody here!
‭Hi!
Hey!
Come here, Mei!
I found it!
Wow.
Someone up there?
Catch some ghostses upstairs?
It's an acorn.
They must like 'em.
Little dust bunnies,
go away right now!
Aah!
Don't be scared, Mei.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
There's nobody here.
Ah!
There.
That's it... easy.
Slowly.
Guess what?!
Something's really
living upstairs after all!
That's wonderful.
Good for you.
I've always wanted to
have a haunted house.
It's been my lifelong dream.
Careful!
Guess what, sis!
I got one!
Ow!
Eh?
Aah!
Mei?
- Ohh.
- Aah!
A couple of fine kids.
Mei, there's nothing
to be frightened about.
Nanny is the lady who
has the farm next door.
She came over to help us out.
Nanny, this is Mei, my sister,
and I'm Satsuki.
Very pleased to meet both of you.
My, my, what smart children.
If I had known what a big hurry you were in
to move, I would've cleaned the house up a bit.
Nanny, you've done so much already.
It really isn't necessary.
Well, you know how it is. I've been
so busy in the rice paddies lately...
Oh my gosh, how did you get all
that black on you?
I had a dust bunny
right in my hand.
Oh! Mei, your feet!
Uh-oh.
...once in a while, to do a little dusting,
you know...
- You got mine black, too!
- Eh?
Aha!
It appears the soot sprites
are hard at work.
What are they?
You mean those black
little fuzzy things
that fly around the house
and disappear upstairs?
Yes. They breed in very old empty houses...
...building invisible nests,
and turning everything into dust.
I could see them, too,
when I was a very small child.
That you two are able to see them
makes me very glad.
It couldn't have been
a spirit, could it?
If they're not sprites, then you
have nothing to be frightened about.
If we all keep smiling, the sprites may
gradually go away and leave this place alone.
Yes. I'm sure that
somewhere up in that ceiling...
...they're busily discussing plans
for leaving the house.
Maybe they really will leave us alone.
Well, what's wrong with them?
With dust bunnies all over the house,
you wouldn't want to go away!
I'm not afraid of dust bunnies.
Well, maybe you can go to the bathroom
by yourself at night.
Ha ha ha!
Come, come! The house needs cleaning up.
So fetch a bucket and go get
some water.
- You mean from the stream?
- Maybe we'll catch a fish!
You wait here, okay?
Did you get any fish?
It's coming out!
- It's coming out, Nanny!
- Good. Very good.
Just keep at it till the water
gets cold.
Right.
Hey, is that for us?
Is that for me?
Tell me what your name is.
Uh, it's for grandma.
Huh?
Grandma?
Yuh-uh-uh.
Hmm?
Mmm!
- Yuh!
- Hey, wait up! Where you going?
Kanta, don't be silly.
Hey, haven't you heard?
You're living in a haunted house!
Go away!
Yuh!
Ha ha ha!
Well, I remember doing the very same thing
when I was his age.
I hate boys...
...but I love Nanny's food better than
anything else in the whole wide world!
Eat all you want.
Thanks for your help!
Bye!
Thank you so much, Nanny.
- Goodbye!
- Bye-bye!
Daddy, I'm scared the wind's going to
make the house fall down.
Maybe it will, but I hope not
because we just moved in.
Ah!
Ha! ‭Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
Hey, come on. What are you waiting for?
You have to laugh loud to scare a spirit.
Ha ha ha!
Hee hee hee!
I'm not scared at all.
Haa! Ha ha ha!
Hey, I'm not! I mean it!
Hah-haa! Ha ha ha!
One, two.
- That's it.  Give it all you got.
- One, two. One, two.
- Come on, yeah.
There we go.
Well, if I may humbly say so,
we're finished.
Yay!
- There we are.
- Get ready to fly, Mei!
Better hold on!
Here we go!
Nanny!
Hi!
Hello!
Where are you pedaling
off to this morning?
We're going to visit mommy
in the hospital!
Well, be sure
to give my regards!
- I know she'll be very happy to see you!
- Bye-bye.
That way, daddy!
That way!
- Good afternoon.
- ‭Oh!
- Mommy!
- My love, I'm so happy to see you.
Daddy took the wrong road,
and we had to come back another way.
Well! Don't be shy.
We got off today from school.
Wonderful.
Mommy, um, daddy told me
tell you he'll be here.
He's probably speaking to the doctor, Mei.
It's so good to be able to see you all.
Please tell me about the new house.
Do you like it?
Yeah.
- Oh! You mean they live upstairs?
- Mm-hmm.
Do you like spirits, mommy?  Even fuzzy ones?
Of course. I wish I could go home with you
and see them right away.
You were right, Mei.
Mm-hmm.
We thought you might not be too happy
about the house being filled with spooks.
Are you happy with them?
- Yep.
- And I'm not afraid of them at all.
Don't tell me you fixed Mei's ponytails
by yourself.
Mm-hmm.
They're beautiful.
You know, you're a very lucky girl.
She gets mad at me almost all the time!
- And that's because you're always jumping around.
- Satsuki, come here.
Why don't you let me
brush your hair for a minute?
I'm glad you let me keep it short.
I want mine short too!
Only when you're my age, Mei!
Satsuki, you have wire for hair, as stubborn
as mine was when I was small girl.
I'll be able to have hair as beautiful
as yours when I become older, won't I?
Of course you will! And I know that because
you're the spitting image of me when I was young.
Hi.
I thought mommy looked a lot better.
A lot better! In fact, I think the doctor
might let her leave in a very short time!
Does a short time mean tomorrow, daddy?
Aw, come on! Tomorrow means tomorrow.
Maybe not tomorrow, but it's pretty soon.
She said when she comes home,
she's only gonna sleep in my own bed.
Hey, what about what you told me: that you were big enough to sleep all by yourself.
Mommy told me it be okay.
Daddy!
Daddy, wake up!
It's morning!
Daddy, get up!
It's Mei!
- Good morning.
- I must have overslept or something.
We get our lunch boxes today.
I'm sorry. I completely forgot.
I made lunch for everybody!
Don't worry about it.
Hey, it's burning!
Just a minute!
Okay, this one's for you.
That one's mine.
Mei, stop that. Sit down and eat.
Go ahead. Wrap it yourself.
Hey! You're late!
- Satsuki!
- Must be time to go.
'Kay!
I can't believe you've made a friend already.
Hey, bet you sit next to her in class.
Yep, and her name's Michiko.
Here I come!
Well, thanks for saying goodbye!
Hi. Sorry.
How come you took so long? We're going to be late!
Daddy, this hat!
Am I a grownup if I wear it?
It looks that way to me.
Where are you off to?
Gonna get some flowers.
Is it lunchtime yet?
I don't think so!
Daddy, look. I'm the flower lady.
Gollywollypogs!
Hmm.
There's no bottom.
Huh?
Wow! Acorn!
Dust bunnies.
Hey.
Huh?
Come back!
Aha!
Hm?
Hey.
Mmm.
Tell me who you are.
Are you a big dust bunny?
Totoro?
That's it. I bet your name's Totoro, isn't it?
So you're really a Totoro.
Totoro.
Sure, I will. Tomorrow.
- Okay, bye!
- See you later!
Daddy, I'm home.
Already? Wait a minute.
How come you're home so late?
I was playing with Michiko.
Where's Mei?
That's funny, I haven't even eaten my lunch...
I think Mei's out back.
Mei!
Mei?
Daddy, over here!
I think I know where Mei went.
Mei?
Mei!
Wake up!
Wake up.
Wake up, Mei! Right now!
You have no business sleeping
in this place.
How come he's gone?
How come who's gone?
Tell me who you lost.
A big Totoro was here with me.
You don't mean a big one, like what's in
our picture books, do you?
Mm-hmm.
And I climbed up on top of him,
and he was furry,
and he had a big mouth,
and there was a little one,
and one this big,
and a great big one sleeping by himself.
Uh-huh?
Hello! Is anybody in there?
Well, I'll be.
What a great hiding place.
Daddy! Mei was just telling
me she saw a big Totoro.
- A real one?
- Mm-hmm.
This way.
Hey, give me a chance.
Here?
Mmm. Mm-hmm.
He was by the big tree a little while ago.
I don't see how he could've gotten away.
Mei! Mei, come back!
Stop laughing!
I really saw him, I'm not lying.
I'm not lying.
Mei.
You don't believe me.
Mm-hmm.
That's where you're wrong.
I believe you're being completely truthful about this.
But I also believe that you met
the king of the forest, Mei.
And meeting him is a sign of good luck.
But there's no guarantee that
you'll see him all the time.
Come on.
- We'll have to go back and pay our respects.
- Where do we find him?
- Well, Miss Mei will find him for us.
- Yeah!
Oh!
Oh, Mei, you're getting heavier
by the minute.
Daddy, the camphor tree.
What a beautiful tree.
I found it.
- You sure that's the one?
- Uh-huh.
What are you waiting
for, daddy? Hurry up!
The hole's not there anymore...
...but I'm sure this is where it was.
You're positive it is?
Mm-hmm.
The opening's completely disappeared.
Well, remember, you can see him
only when he wants you to.
- Will we see him?
- Maybe.
But I want to meet him.
You never can tell, if we're lucky enough.
What a beautiful tree it is.
This tree's been here, well,
since before anyone can remember.
You know, a long time ago,
man and trees were the best of friends.
It's actually because of this tree that
I decided to buy our house in the first place,
and you can bet mommy will
like it when she sees it.
So, whadda ya say we thank the king of the forest
and get back for our lunch.
I have to meet Michiko after lunch
to get ready for an exam.
I'm coming, too.
Attention!
Thank you for all you've done for Mei.
Please look after her and protect her forever.
- Thank you so much.
- Last one home's a rotten egg.
- Hey, that's not fair! You cheated!
Wait!
Hey!
Hey, wait up!
Dear Mother,
You're never going to believe this, but today,
under that giant tree on the top of the hill,
Mei actually met a ghost: Totoro.
Daddy says it was
the king of the forest.
Well, whoever he was, I really want
to meet him.
Kanta, you'd better hurry up,
or you'll be late.
Okay!
There.
Huh?
Mei? What...
Excuse me.
Yes, Satsuki?
I-it's my sister Mei.
Oh my gosh!
- What's with the new girl?
- Who is she?
What's she going to do?
Is she gonna bring her back here?
Nanny! Nanny, what happened?
Dear, I'm sorry, but she demanded
to be with her sister and simply won't listen.
But I'm going to be--
Mei, now, you promised to be a good girl...
...because daddy was gonna be at the university
and wasn't gonna be able to take care of you.
I have a couple hours left before I can come home,
and Nanny's been very nice to watch you.
Our Mei has been a very good little girl, eh?
Well, I better ask permission
for her to come inside.
Because her mother's going to be in the hospital...
...Satsuki will be taking care of her
sister Mei for a short while.
Is that clear for everybody?
Yes, ma'am.
What's that a picture of, Mei?
A Totoro picture.
Shh!
Could you be a little more quiet
about it?
Bye-bye.
Want to come over and play?
If I can...
but I might miss the club meeting, is that okay?
- Come whenever you can.  See ya!
- See ya!
- Bye, Mei.
- Goodbye.
We'd better walk fast,
or we're going to get wet.
'Kay.
Oh, no! Hurry!
Oh, my god.
Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Come on.
Wow. What do we do now?
If it's not too much trouble,
could we stay until it stops raining?
Uh...
Uh, thanks.
Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
We were pretty lucky, huh?
Ha ha! That's funny.
It's got holes in it.
Uh-oh. Daddy left his umbrella.
Hey, we could bring it back to him!
I just forgot because I forgot.
How can you forget your umbrella
when it's raining outside?
Ow!
- Even you can't be that stupid.
- Mom!
You were probably playing with it,
and broke it in half or something.
I did not!
Hmm?
Y-y-yii!
Excuse me! Is anybody home?
Satsuki, what are you doing here?
Grandma.
- Thank you for taking care of Mei.
- Oh, don't be ridiculous. She was a treasure.
Well, besides that, we wanted to
bring back the umbrella we borrowed.
But--Kanta's umbrella?
Why would he give you
this beat-up thing?
It came in handy, because we didn't have one...
...but I'm afraid he got soaking wet.
Anyway, please thank him for us.
I will. I'm always telling him to wash the mud off,
so some rain did him no harm at all.
Are you on your way
to meet your father?
Yes, ma'am.
Well, you give him my regards.
- Bye-bye.
- ‭Bye.
Did someone come to the door?
I didn't hear anything.
Oh, boy, we made it!
Thank you.
Getting onboard or not?
All right, let's go.
Daddy wasn't on that one, right?
I'm sure he'll be on the next one.
Do you want to go back
to Nanny's house and wait?
What's the matter?
- Mei, you're sleepy.
- Uh-uh.
Aw, come on now...
I told you it might be a while.
You don't want to go
to Nanny's and wait?
It won't be long, I'm sure the bus
will come soon. Just hang in there.
Well, I guess they were delayed,
but I hope not.
Come on.
I bet... you're Totoro.
Oh, we have another umbrella,
if you want.
Go ahead, take it.
Come on! I'm going to drop Mei.
You put it over your head like that.
Huh?
The bus is here!
Mei, wa-wasn't that umbrella
he took with him daddy's?
Thank you.
How nice of you to meet me!
Daddy!
I'm sorry, but the train was late.
That's why I missed the first bus.
You weren't worried about me, were you?
I saw him! I saw him!
He was right beside me at the bus stop!
Me, too!  We saw Catbus too!
Uh... uh...
- Oh, and gigantic arms.
- Great big eyeballs, too.
- It was scary.
- I was scared.
- We saw Totoro! We saw Totoro!
-  We saw Totoro! We saw Totoro!
Hey, anyone want a ride?
- I do!
- Okay, here we go!
Dear mother,
I'm surprised I can write to you at all,
'cause my heart is still beating so fast.
Mei and I had something incredible
happen today.
We both met Totoro!
I really saw him!
He even gave us a gift.
It was a package wrapped up in
bamboo leaves and tied with dragon whiskers.
We opened it as soon as we got home,
and guess what was in it!
Magic nuts and seeds.
We've decided to plant them all out in the front,
because someday they'll be tall and beautiful.
Mei just...
...sits there every day,
waiting for them to sprout,
but they don't seem
to want to grow.
I can't wait to see
what they'll be like.
Oh, yes, Mei sends her love and wanted
to make sure you saw her drawing.
It's going to be summer vacation soon,
and we'll be out of school.
I love you, mother.
And please get well soon.
Come on, get off.
That's it! I said get off!
Come on, it's bedtime.
Daddy, will the plants come out?
I mean will they come out tomorrow?
That's tough to say.
Perhaps Totoro will be able to say
if they will.
Good night.
Wake up, Mei.
- But isn't that where we planted--
- Mm-hmm.
Oh! Ow!
It worked!
Yay!
We did it! Yay!
Yah!
- Aah!
- ‭Now we know what makes the wind blow!
Hm.
Huh?
What happened to the tree?
- Hey!
- No way!
We did it! We did it!
Yay!
It was only a dream.
It wasn't a dream.
It was only a dream!
It wasn't a dream!
We did it!
Telegram!
Hello!
Hello! Anyone home?
Hmm.
Maybe not.
Nanny!
Over here, Mei.
That one's perfect.
Ahh...!
About how ripe is this?
That's ripe.
Wow.
Your vegetable garden is more like
a mountain of treasure.
Thanks to mother nature.
Let's take a little rest,
shall we?
There we are, nice and cold.
Michiko will be jealous.
Mmm.
It's amazing.
They've absorbed lots of wonderful things
from the sun...
...and that's what makes them so good for
the body and good for the soul.
They wouldn't help my mother, would they?
Of course they would.
My vegetable garden is bound to make
anyone feel better in no time at all.
Our mother's coming home this week
from the hospital.
And she's gonna come sleep with me
under my covers.
That's wonderful.
She's able to come back, is she?
Mm-mm, she's coming home to spend a couple of
days but then has to go right back there.
I suppose she has to be careful.
Yes, she has.
But we'll fatten her up
on my fresh vegetables.
I'm gonna give mommy this corn
I picked for her specially.
And I'm sure she'll love you for it.
Mm-hmm.
Mailman gave me this telegram
because you were out.
Here.
But daddy won't be home from
the university till after 9:00.
Open it now then.
A telegram is serious business.
Mm-hmm.
It's from my mother's doctor
at the hospital.
Please contact me.
What's that supposed to mean?
Is something wrong with her or not?
I know something awful's
happened to her.
What am I supposed to do
if my father's not home?
Listen, you must be calm.
Have you any way of
telephoning your father?
I have the number of his research lab,
but we don't have a telephone to call him.
Take them back to your mother's place,
and let them use the phone to reach their father.
Do you understand?
Don't panic, but go quickly.
Mm-hmm.
Mei, you make sure you stay put
at my house!
Mei! Mei!
Hey, Mei, don't follow me!
Go to Nanny's house.
Oh.
Hello, operator.
I'd like to make a long-distance call,
please.
It's very important.
It's number 1354 at station 12.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Your friend is very pretty.
What lovely hair.
Hello.
Yes.
Can you put me through to the main
lecture room of the anthropology school?
To Professor Kusokabi.
Please hurry.
Yes, yes. I'm his daughter.
It was from the hospital, daddy!
I'm so worried!
Whoa, whoa. Slow down.
From the hospital?
Oh, okay. It's all right.
I think I understand.
Now, I'm going to call the hospital.
What's happened to mommy?
Tell me everything's gonna be all right!
There's no need to worry. I'm going to check
with the hospital and call you right back, okay?
- Okay?
- Uh-huh.
- You stay where you are.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm hanging up, so you stay right there.
He'll be calling back, so is it all right if
I stay right here by the telephone and wait?
You take all the time you need.
Hey, where are you?
Uh-oh.
Oh, no!
I'm gonna give this corn to my mommy!
Go away!
You just better stop it right now!
Mei, the hospital said that mommy's
condition isn't very good...
...so she isn't going to be
coming home just yet.
But why?
Mei, what can we do?
If she came home now,
we'd only make it worse.
It would not!
But she'll be able
to come home real soon.
No!
All right then! Be that way!
Let's see if she dies!
No!
Don't be dumb, Mei!
Oh, I give up!
You're so stupid!
Come on, Mei.
Waah!
I'm not stupid!
Waa!
Waah!
Wah!
Waa!
I took care of the rest of the washing.
Come on, now.
It isn't the end of the world.
Your old Nanny's here to help.
Let's see that beautiful smile.
Your father's going to be stopping off at
the hospital on his way home, eh?
What I heard was that your mother
only caught a small cold, mm-hmm.
She'll be home next weekend,
I believe.
That's what they said last time, too.
It'll be a little visit, just a few
days to see what's wrong with her.
It's just a cold.
What are me and Mei going to do
if mommy dies?
Uh, uh...
What are we going to do, Nanny?
There, there.
Don't worry.
Your mother's not going to die.
Hush. She'd never leave two
such beautiful children.
She loves you too much for that.
Don't cry.
Nanny will stay with you
until your father comes home.
Mei!
Where are you?
Mei, come back!
- Did you see her anywhere?
- No sign at all.
She wasn't at the bus stop?
That's very strange.
Where could she possibly have gone off to?
Maybe she's angry about this morning.
We had a bad argument and--
Maybe she went off to visit mommy
in the hospital!
But the hospital's so far from here.
It's-- oh, my heavens!
Why, it would take a grown man
three hours to get there.
Hey!
Oh, my goodness!
Please, you must get your father right now.
You must tell him that
little Mei has disappeared.
How could you do something so stupid, Mei?
You always get lost.
Mei!
I'm sorry to bother you, but you--
Well, you haven't seen a little girl
come by this way, have you?
She's my sister, about 5 years old.
Well, seems to me I remember someone.
Eh, yes, near as I can recall,
she went that way.
Maybe she went through the forest.
And, then again, she might've gone
in the other direction.
Uh, you're you sure it was your sister?
All sorts of folks come by here,
but I don't see them.
Mei, I'm scared.
Thank you!
Mei!
- Please stop!
- Aah!
- Hey, are you crazy, kid?
- I'm looking for my sister.
Have you seen a little girl
wandering around?
I'm afraid not.
Mei is her name, and
she's about five years old.
She probably got herself lost.
We haven't seen anyone, have we?
- I think she's going to Shechi Kokoyama.
- We just came from there...
...but we haven't come across anybody for
the last couple of hours.
I'm sorry.
Well, um, thank you.
By the way, where are you from?
Um, Matsuko.
You walked from there to here?
- That's over three hours away!
- Yeah!
Well, good luck, kid.
I hope you find her!
Satsuki, wait!
Come here!
Kanta!
We haven't found her yet.
How about you?
Nothing.
Hey, my dad's got everyone
in the village searching for her...
...so you go home, and I'll bike
to Shechi Kokoyama, okay?
Okay?
But I'm afraid if she goes to visit mommy's hospital,
she'll completely lose her--
Wait a second!
Somebody found some sandals
by the lake, half an hour ago.
There's no way she could get past
all those people without somebody noticing.
Oh!
Hey, don't worry!
Nobody said they were Mei's sandals!
Did you find her yet?
Go back a bit over towards your right,
we haven't covered that area!
Hey, you have any poles left?
There's Satsuki.
Eh?
Look.
Mei! Mei!
Look, Satsuki.
Is it hers?
It's not hers.
Wha?
Ohh...
Merciful heavens.
You know, Satsuki,
for a while I thought it might be Mei's.
Mom, I told you, you jump to
conclusions too fast.
Hey, boys! Forget it! Stop!
It isn't hers!
So, what do we do now?
Well, we keep on looking, that's what.
Well, whatever you do, you better hurry up.
It's going to be dark soon.
I'm grateful to you all.
I know it's tough work...
- ...but if you could keep searching--
- Aw, don't worry. We understand.
Hey, don't you think we
should call the police?
Well, I don't know.
Do you think the police could--
Please, where are you going?
Totoro...
I beg you, please protect Mei.
She'll be lost and probably scared.
Please believe me, I'll be good for
the rest of my life if I can just see her again.
What?
Totoro!
Totoro, ‭Mei's lost somewhere!
I looked and looked, but
I can't find her anywhere!
Oh, please, you have to help me find her.
She's probably alone somewhere,
crying and upset.
Oh, Totoro, I'm scared.
What?
He wouldn't be able to.
But how come nobody sees the bus?
Oh...
Oh!
Next stop, little sister.
Mei, where are you?
But how does he make it do that?
Ohh...
Mei!
But, sis, where are you?
- Satsuki!
- Mei!
There you are!
Satsuki!
Oh, Mei.
I'm sorry.
Tell me one thing:
were you bringing that corn to the hospital?
Mm-hmm.
Next stop, Shechi Kokoyama Hospital.
You mean we can go to mom's hospital?
You're wonderful!
I'm sorry.
It was all because of my silly cold
that the hospital sent you that telegram.
The grief it must've caused all of you.
I hope you can forgive me.
It was simply a bureaucratic mistake.
I'm sure it wasn't terribly traumatic
for either of the girls.
It just means you'll be home next weekend.
They understand.
I wouldn't be at all surprised
if they suffered more than we know...
...in particular Satsuki, because
she's so smart and sensitive.
Hmm, could be right.
You'd better be careful
after I get home because...
...I intend to spoil them rotten
for a while!
Oh, no!
Look. Mommy's laughing.
- She seems pretty healthy to me.
- Yep!
Oh, I can't wait to get up
on my feet again.
Neither can we.
Oh.
Hmm.
Now, that's weird.
Oh!
What happened?
Well, I'm not sure, but I could've sworn that
I saw both the girls up in the treetop laughing.
That might not be as crazy as you think...
have a look!
For mother.
Totoro
Who leaves the seeds
For you to find?
Follow them
And you will see
A treasure there
Then plant the seeds
And help them grow
It may seem like a dream
But things are not what they seem
Now begins a new adventure
For you
And you'll be with Totoro
Totoro
Living in the forest trees
For such a very, very long time
There you'll be with Totoro
Totoro
You only see him
When you're very young
A magical adventure for you
It's magic for you
Rain tumbles down
The bus is late
Suddenly
A furry wet giant
Is by your side
Don't be afraid
Just open wide
Your umbrella for him
Watch him play in the rain
Now begins a new adventure
For you
And you'll be with Totoro
Totoro
And on a moonlit night
He plays a magic flute in the sky
There you'll be with Totoro
Totoro
You only see him
When you're very young
A magical adventure for you
It's magic for you